<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>development on Hubert Choo</title><link>https://hubertchoo.github.io/tags/development/</link><description>Recent content in development on Hubert Choo</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>&lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://hubertchoo.github.io/tags/development/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>FPGA Video Denoising and Segmentation (Y2 Summer Project)</title><link>https://hubertchoo.github.io/posts/2023/07/fpga-video-denoising-and-segmentation-y2-summer-project/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hubertchoo.github.io/posts/2023/07/fpga-video-denoising-and-segmentation-y2-summer-project/</guid><description>Y2 Summer Project Introduction For the Imperial EEE Department, the Y2 Summer Term project was to:
Design and build a balancing rover (Segway), that can autonomously navigate and map a maze, with the assistance of three beacons. Finally, the shortest path through the maze should be computed and followed. A prototype of the design must be built and tested on the artificial maze in the lab. The maze is laid out with light strips on an arena.</description></item><item><title>My Boards and My Software</title><link>https://hubertchoo.github.io/posts/2023/07/my-boards-and-my-software/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hubertchoo.github.io/posts/2023/07/my-boards-and-my-software/</guid><description>The FPGA Boards I Use DE10-Lite MAX10 10M50DAF484C7G Device DE10-Nano Intel Cyclone® V SE 5CSEBA6U23I7 device 800MHz Dual-core ARM Cortex-A9 hard processor The Daughter Boards I Use D8M-GPIO 8 Mega Pixel Digital Camera Package with GPIO interface The Software I Use Quartus Prime Lite 18.1 NIOS II Embedded Design Suite (EDS) ModelSim - Intel FPGA Starter Edition 10.5b</description></item><item><title>Setting Up This Website</title><link>https://hubertchoo.github.io/posts/2023/07/setting-up-this-website/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hubertchoo.github.io/posts/2023/07/setting-up-this-website/</guid><description>Step 1. Install Hugo, Go, Dart Sass Go to Hugo Installation and download the appropriate version for your OS and architecture.
I used the Winget Packet Manager to install the Hugo Extended Edition.
winget install Hugo.Hugo.Extended Step 2. Set Up Github Pages with Hugo Follow this guide to set up Github Pages for use with Hugo.
A Github Action is also set up to deploy the website automatically with new pushes.</description></item></channel></rss>